Shreyas Vedpathak

04 Jan 2001 | shreyasvedpathak@gmail.com | 9881898291 | 411002 Pune, India

LinkedIn ID: shreyasvedpathak | Github ID: shreyasvedpathak | Website: shreyasvedpathak.github.io

PROFILE

1+ years of expertise building and implementing deep learning algorithms using TensorFlow and PyTorch is required. Excited about increasing studies into artificial intelligence. I have the solid technical expertise as well as an academic background in Engineering, Statistics, and Machine Learning.

EDUCATION

2018 – presentBachelor of TechnologyPune, IndiaMIT World Peace University □

Current CGPA: 9.43

SKILLS

C • C++ • Python • Tensorflow • PyTorch • Scikit Learn • MySQL • MongoDB • Tableau

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Aug 2021 – present

Mentor

California, USA

DeepLearning.AI ☑

Mar 2021 – Jun 2021 Pune, India Data Analyst Intern

Analytics Domain ☑

PUBLICATIONS

Jun 2021 Genomics, High Performance Computing and Machine Learning

UIJRT (United International Journal for Research & Technology)

This paper aims to explore in a very uncomplicated manner, what exactly is genomics, where does high performance computing and machine learning come into picture, current applications and discuss potential future scope.

Nov 2020

PCOcare PCOS Detection and Prediction using Machine Learning Algorithms 2

Bioscience Biotechnology Research Communications

Using 5 Machine Learning Algorithms, this research attempts to provide a system that can aid in the early diagnosis and prediction of PCOS therapy based on an optimal and minimal set of parameters.

AWARDS

Nov 2020 Best Paper Award ☑

International Conference on Intelligent Systems, Data Science and Computing

Best Research Paper Award in Machine Learning Track.

PROJECTS

May 2021 – present Segmentation of Fire and Smoke in Nano-Satellite Imagery using Mask R-CNN

and Res-UNet

Research Project

Image Segmentation Algorithm: Mask Region-Based Convolutional Neural Network (Mask R-CNN), UNet, and Deep Residual U-NET. Successfully distinguished natural entities such as clouds, snow, rivers, and smoke created by a fire.

Jul 2021 - Jul 2021 Hardhat Detection: Dynamically Colored Bounding Boxes

Private Project

Detecting hardhats in an image/video/live stream and offering security approval based on

the color of the hardhat.

Jun 2021 – Jul 2021 Loan Management System - Flask API

Private Project

Simple loan management API made with FLASK as the backend and SQLite as the

database. Token-based authentication, with Flask Blueprints for future scaling.

Nov 2020 - Nov 2020 Dogs vs Cats - Using Keras Functional API ☑

Keras Functional API was used to create a simple Tensorflow-based Convolutional Neural

Network model.

Oct 2020 - Nov 2020 PCOcare: PCOS Detection & Prediction using ML

Research Project

A system is proposed that can aid in the early diagnosis and prediction of PCOS treatment. Random Forest, SVM, Logistic Regression, Gaussian Nave Bayes, and K Neighbours are five different machine learning classifiers. The CHI square approach is

used for feature engineering.

ORGANISATIONS

Pune, India Google Developers Group

Member

Pune, India Society of Biological Engineers

Technical Team Member

COURSES

Machine Learning by Andrew Ng

Stanford University

TensorFlow: Advanced Techniques

deeplearning.ai

Generative Adversarial Networks Specialization

deeplearning.ai

Generative Deep Learning with TensorFlow

deeplearning.ai

INTERESTS

• Watching Movies/Series

• Image Editing

Video Editing

REFERENCES

Dr. Kalpana Thakre, *Professor*, Sinhgad College of Engineering, Pune kalpana_sunil@yahoo.com, 9922411355

Shilpa Sonawani, Associate Professor, MIT World Peace University, Pune shilpa.sonawani@mitwpu.edu.in, 8698955002